Aurel Jared C. Dantis

Diliman, Quezon City, PHJareddantis@gmail.comdantis.me/linkedin.com/in/jareddantis

Profile

Computer science graduate with a passion for the visual arts and a desire to unite timely information with good design. Has experience creating websites, promotional materials, and other media for various purposes, ranging from personal projects to academic requirements and events.

Education University of the Philippines Diliman

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science · 2019 — present

Philippine Science High School Main Campus

Secondary ⋅ 2013 — 2019

University of the Philippines Integrated School

Primary ⋅ 2006 — 2013

Skills	Web Development	Programming Languages
	Vue.js, Nuxt	HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript
	Tailwind CSS	Python 3
	Bootstrap, jQuery	С
	Flask	
	Figma	DoyOne ete
	SQL	DevOps, etc.
		Docker, Portainer
	Adobe Creative Cloud	Git version control
		Cloudflare (DNS, Argo Tunnels)
	Photoshop	Linux/UNIX proficiency
	Illustrator	ZeroTier, Tailscale
	Lightroom	Nginx
	Premiere Pro	

Experience

Web Development Intern, UP-PGC CFB

Jun 2022 — Jul 2022

Helped enhance *GxBLearn*, a website for teaching the basics of bioinformatics, by incorporating interactive Biopython examples that could run in the browser, no Python installation required.

Branding & Creatives Manager, CURSOR++

Sep 2021 — May 2022

Designed branding and digital media for the Academic Year 2021-2022 installment of CURSOR++, a series of internal workshops geared towards developing professional, technical, and soft skills of UP CURSOR members.

WebUpdates Team Head, UP CURSOR 2122A

Sep 2021 — Jan 2022

Designed the new UP CURSOR website for 2022 and led the team responsible for the website design and the online announcement materials for the UP Association of Computer Science Majors (UP CURSOR).

Research & publications

Developing a Browser Extension for the Automated

2023

Detection of Deceptive Patterns in Cookie Banners

Adorna, J. H., Dantis, A. J., Feria, R., Figueroa, L. L., & Solamo, R.

Presented at the 2023 Workshop on Computation: Theory and Practice in Chitose, Hokkaido, Japan. Pending publication.

Awards & citations

University Scholar

University of the Philippines Diliman

Oblation Scholarship Awardee

2019

University of the Philippines Diliman

Undergraduate Merit Scholarship Awardee

2019

Science Education Institute, Department of Science and Technology

Director's Lister

2013 - 2019

Philippine Science High School Main Campus

Workshops & conferences attended

Iskolart

Nov 2018

Conference on the application of design in an educational context, and the state of art in current Philippine society.

PSHSS 2018 Science Research Summit

Sep — Oct 2018

Convention of PSHS scholars from all over the Philippines that aims to increase the community's knowledge and appreciation of Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM).

Graphika Manila 2018

Feb 2018

Annual conference on the current state of and trends in design, with talks from veterans of various fields in the industry.

TEDxYouth@PSHSMain

May 2017

Conference that aims to spark discussion and connection through talks given by experts from various fields, from mathematics to the arts.

Projects Ariadne

https://github.com/wsg-ariadne

Browser extension for detecting deceptive patterns on websites using machine learning. Presented as undergraduate thesis project at WCTP 2023 (see previous Research & Publications section).

Extension written in Vue.js 3 & Tailwind CSS.

Dashboard written in Nuxt 3 & Tailwind CSS and secured with Auth0.

ML models created with NLTK & Keras on Python 3.

API written in Flask & PostgreSQL and deployed as a Docker container on university-hosted Ubuntu virtual private server.

Blanco

https://blanco.dantis.me

Discord bot written in Python 3 that allows users to play back high-quality music in a Discord voice channel. Written with Nextcord and deployed as a Docker container on Google Cloud Compute Engine.

General Weighted Average (GWA) Calculator

https://calc.dantis.me

Web app that lets students quickly estimate their current class standing. Written in Vue.js 2, made with Vuetify, and deployed on Netlify.

Playman

https://playman.dantis.me

Web app for managing your Spotify playlists, even while on the go. Supports shuffling, merging, backups and more. Written in Vue.js 2, made with Vuetify, and deployed on Netlify.